Kareem Rizk

kareem.magdy5@gmail.com * 202 621 4174 * Alexandria VA, 22310

Executive summary:

A novice web developer, designer, and journalist for 8 years with a special passion for coding and IT. Seeking a job as a front-end developer with knowledge and practical skills in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Git, and Github. Currently pursuing my passion for expanding my capabilities at George Washington University's web development bootcamp.

Technical skills

- JavaScript (Vanilla JS, JQuery, (learning React))
- HTML (Semantic HTML)
- CSS (Bootstrap and responsive design.
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint and Access)
- Python (libraries: Matplot, Seaborn)
- Git and Github
- WordPress

Experience:

George Washington University Bootcamp

November 2021 - Present

Full Stack developer certificate program

- Building and styling static web pages with semantic HTML and CSS.
- Using Git to start projects, track changes, and host code via remote servers.
- Deploying a website to GitHub pages.
- Improving website interactivity by using Javascript and its frameworks like React.
- Applying the accepted and standard basics of social coding—including source control, and issue tracking.

MBN – Alhurra channel website

April 2018 - June 2021

Multimedia producer

- Retrieved the website from the production server, updated and modified pages and indexes. Pushed the updated pages to the production server.
- Acted as admin support to the webpage to grant permissions for new producers.
- Implemented modifications requested by users.
- Translated articles from Persian and English into Arabic.
- Pitched compelling story ideas to the editorial management team.
- Ensured accuracy of facts, grammar and spelling prior to review for publication.
- Monitored news sources to keep informed of related regional and international news.

The National Interest

Jan 2019 - June 2019

Intern

- Wrote reports and <u>articles</u> covering the MENA region.
- Translated from Arabic, Persian into English.

Iran Disinformation (Bethesda, Maryland)

July 2019 – December 2019

Translator

- Downloaded and manipulated/cleaned multiple Relational Databases from several websites to be integrated into my weekly reports for the MENA region.
- Visualized Databases using Tableau, Python's Matplot library and Seaborn.
- Did research from several web resources and downloaded dynamic data, to conduct research on human rights and democratic transition.
- Translated from Persian into English and Arabic.
- Fact checked the Iranian propaganda.
- Validated and verified data published on the Iranian regime media against global trusted sources, like world bank.

Arabic Post (Istanbul, Turkey)

Jan 2018 – April 2018

Journalist

- Wrote stories on politics (including Iranian affairs), lifestyle, culture and history.
- Translated articles from Persian and English into Arabic.
- Covered the Arabic affairs especially the Egyptian
- Monitored news sources to keep informed of related regional and international news.
- Ensured all articles, videos, interviews and other content are well organized, timely, balanced.

Elwatan News (Giza, Egypt)

January 2015- August 2015

Journalist

- Covered the Iranian nuclear deal in 2015, through translating news from Persian media.
- Covered world news, particularly focusing on the Middle East.
- Served as an editor.
- Translated news articles from English and Persian into Arabic.

Education:

GW University Web Development bootcamp Faculty of Dar-Alulum, Cairo University

November 2021 - Present June 2013

Bachelor of Arts in Arabic Language and Islamic Studies

Languages: Arabic, English, Persian